Guide to the Wilbur Richard Knorr Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wilbur Richard Knorr papers
1963-1997
SC0933
Knorr, Wilbur Richard, 1945-
60 Linear feet
The papers document Knorr's career as scholar and professor and include lectures, research notes, publications, class files (syllabi, student papers, class evaluations, course readers, etc.), photographic copies of sources and maps, and microfilm of source materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The collection was given to the Stanford University Archvies by the estate of Wilbur Richard Knorr in 1997.
Information about Access
The electronic files in accession 1997-196 are closed pending processing. The collection is otherwise open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Wilbur Richard Knorr, historian of science and the classics, was educated at Harvard (B.A. in 1966 and Ph. D. in 1973). He taught at the University of California in Berkeley and at Brooklyn College before joining the Stanford faculty 1979 as an assistant professor in the History of Science program, which he helped to develop. Although his interests were extraordinarily broad, his focus was on the history of ancient Greek mathematics and its medieval continuations. He died in 1997.
Description of the Collection
The papers document Knorr's career as scholar and professor and include lectures, research notes, publications, class files (syllabi, student papers, class evaluations, course readers, etc.), photographic copies of sources and maps, and microfilm of source materials. The materials were received in three accessions; accession 1997-172 is unprocessed and not included in this guide.
Access Terms
Knorr, Wilbur Richard, 1945-; Mathematics, Ancient
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1994-048
  - Gedding, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - Princeton G99 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Garrett 99 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Latin Astronomy Books; Manuscript copys (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Rational Diameters and the Discovery of Incommensurability" 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AMS (American Mathematics Society) meeting San Diego correspondence 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AMS "Rational" draft and transparencies 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Sacrobosco's Quadrans" and correspondence 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Sacrobosco's Quadrans" notes 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Knorr "Latin Sources of Quadrans Vetus" 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Knorr "Latin Sources… " as sent 1996 -1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AMS Euclid papers 1995 -1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Knorr academic resume, articles (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Knorr references (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Solar Tables in the Tradition of 13th C. Tracts…" draft, photographs 11/1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "On Archimedes' Lemma" and "Euclid and Eudoxus: Origin of…Proportion" working drafts 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - miscellaneous articles (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Knorr "Library of John of London" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Knorr "The Commentators and Mr. Cameron: Observations on Mathematical Studies in Late Antiquity" 8/1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Knorr "Archimedes' Phantom Lemma" 1995 -1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bacon and St. Cloud (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Knorr "Roger Bacon's Kalendarium" 4/1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Knorr Archimedes papers (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "The Ancient Tradition of Geometric Problems" 7/1981, revised 5/1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Knorr "The Ancient Tradition of Geometric Problems" 1/1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Knorr "The Ancient Tradition of Geometric Problems" 11/1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Knorr "The Ancient Tradition of Geometric Problems" 1/1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Knorr "Sacrobosco" reprint 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy copy - Lilienfeld 144 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy copy - Erfurt Mss Q351, Q369 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy copy - Vienna 5508 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Medical Mss (MacKinney) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Vienna 2315 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Gonville and Caius 141/191 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Kk.IV.7, Mm.4.43 (1298) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Kk.1.1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Ii.1.13 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - manuscript copy - Corpus Christi 347 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - manuscript copy - Pembroke 278 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - manuscript copy - Dated Mss (CUL and BL) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - London - BL. Harley 4350 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Harley 531 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Sloane 3281, Add 17810, Sloane 2435 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford CCC 41 - John of London's Astronomy, etc. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Canon Miscellaneous 161 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford MS. Laud. Misc. 644, q 13N7195 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Laud. Miscellaneous 644 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Selden Supr. 26 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - Merton 280, Ashmolean 341, Estense/Modena (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - Glasgow Hunter 205 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Glasgow 369/391 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican 4572 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican 3114 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican Pal. Lat 1400 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican MSS, Vatican Reg. Lat. 1312 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican MSS (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican Pal. Lat. 1149, Medical (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - manuscript copy - Bruges 528 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - manuscript copy - Copen. GKS 277, 20 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - manuscript copy - Morgan 970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - manuscript copy - Morgan Picture Book, 1250 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - manuscript copy - Columbia X88.AR.512 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - manuscript copy - Columbia MSS - MS.21 Aristotle, MS.156 Euclid, MS.165 -2 Euclid (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - manuscript copy - Yale Medical #11 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - manuscript copy - DC - MSS (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - manuscript copy - Harvard Typ. 414 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - manuscript copy - Florence BNC 639 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - manuscript copy - Florence Laur. CV174 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - manuscript copy - Madrid 10.009 Toledo Tables (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - manuscript copy - Sacrobosco Folkerts (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - F.S. Pedersen - Copenhagen Menso correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Furinghetti and Somaglia "Italian Mathematics and Europe in the Late 19th Century" 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Knorr correspondence (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Huntington, HAD (Historical Astronomy Division, American Astronomy Society) and Getty 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Democritus on Mathematical and Physical Shapes" draft and notes (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Knorr correspondence (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Harvard MS Latin 36 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Harvard Ptyp 228 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Nuremberg (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - Royal 1.C.2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - Paris Ste. Genevieve 15, Latin Bible (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - London ADD 54180 - La Somme le Roy (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - London BL. ADD. 16905 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - BL Burney 275 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Paris Arsenal 590 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - London ADD 17341 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN Lat. 1023 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Tours 558: Gratien (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Honore (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - London BL. Add 30380 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN 7475, Sacrobosco (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - NYPL #69, Sacrobosco (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican LAT. URB. 1428, 1408 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - Baltimore Walters Art Gallery (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Knorr notes: 2/14/94, 2/16/94, 8/9/93, 8/20/93 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Tornai #87 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Brussels 2910 -20 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Cambridge Fitzwilliam, McClean 166 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - Copenhagen 1810.4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Verdun 25 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Lincoln Cathedral 148, Sacrobosco, etc. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Berlin Q898 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - London - BL ADD. 26770 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Neufchatel - Bible de Foncarmont (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Rouen MSS (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Rouen BIBL. MUN. 245 (A190) - Fescamp Antiphonarium XIII.S (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - Paris NAL 1242 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7281 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN 534 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Paris MSS (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - BN 16658 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - BN Lat. 16210, 15125 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - BN Lat. 15185, Paris Bible (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 16,655; Peter of Limoges CUL II.3.3 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 14070 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN 7374A (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7420A (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - manuscript copy - BN 7363; S.B. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7437 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7366; S.B. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7333 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - manuscript copy - BN 7413/ 1,2 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - manuscript copy - BN 7196/ 7194 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - manuscript copy - BN 7416B (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - Colmar 414 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Rennes 593 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Florence LAUR. PLUT. 1856 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Vienna 2367 (1292 -95) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - Paris NA.1893 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - BL Egerton 844, 1292 - (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Salamanca 2662 (1292 -95) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Harley 13 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - BL Harley 3647 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN 7421 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Florence BN II.J.10 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Basel O.II.7 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Stockholm X.767 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Princeton Garrett 99 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - BL Harley 3735 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - Florence BNC. MAGL. II iii 24 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Sorbonne 595 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - BL. Royal 12.C.xvii (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Ashmole 1522 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - Florence 18/2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Florence 18/1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Glasgow: Hunter 444 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Tanner 192 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Ii.3.3 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Ii.3.3 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Copenhagen 447 (1296 -99) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7298 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Ste. Genevieve 1043 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Royal 12.C.ix (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - Milan H75 sup. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - CUL Ii.1.17 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - manuscript copy - Paris 7195 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Berlin F.6 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Madrid 8918, Escorial O.II.10 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - Montpellier 323 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - Bruges 522 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - manuscript copy - Vatican 1414 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Lyell 89, Toledo Tables (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - manuscript copy - Cambrai A932; Toledo Tables and Thetrica; CUL Ii.1.17 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - manuscript copy - Paris BN 1624, Toledo Tables (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - manuscript copy - Oxford Selden 78 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - manuscript copy - Darmstadt 2661, 765 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - manuscript copy - Nuremberg Cent V64; Toledo Tables (from F.S. Pedersen 8/1994) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - manuscript copy - Copenhagen 2759, (1292 -95) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - manuscript copy - Munich CLM 353 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Knorr "Archimedes", "Le Savior Grec (Flammarion)", "The Wrong Text of Euclid: On Heiberg's Text and its Alternatives" (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - manuscript copy - Royal 7F8 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - miscellaneous articles and papers (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - manuscript copy - Corpus Christi 221, Oxford (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - manuscript copy - Bodl. 464 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - manuscript copy - Bodl. 464 (additional) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - manuscript copy - BL Cotton VESP. AII (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - miscellaneous articles and papers (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - miscellaneous articles and papers (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - photographs of manuscript sources and maps - prints and negatives (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - manuscript slides - Milan; Montpelier; Munich; New Haven; New York (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - manuscript slides - Princeton; Rouen; San Marino, CA; Stockholm; Vatican (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - manuscript slides - London (British Library) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - manuscript slides - lecture slides; Baltimore; Basel; Berlin; Bruge (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cambridge, MA; Cambridge, UK; Copenhagen; Florence; Glasgow (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Knorr "Pseudo-Euclidean Reflections in Ancient Optics..." draft and reprints (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Knorr "Pseudo-Euclidean…" related and correspondence (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - miscellaneous notes and articles (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - optics correspondence 1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - optics, Knorr "Pseudo-Euclidean… " 10/1990, other papers (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - mechanics papers, correspondence (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - mounted photographs of manuscript (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - slides and photocopies of manuscript (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - articles, reprints, papers, NSF proposal evaluation 1987 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ANRW optics 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B (Cosmology in the Middle Ages) student work 1982 - (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B student work 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B course pack 1990 -1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B evaluations (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B Roger Bacon lecture notes (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B Galileo lecture notes 1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1990 -1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1989 -1990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1988 -1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1985 -1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1984 -1985 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1983 -1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1982 -1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1981 -1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138B notes, student work 1980 -1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Murdoch science and religion papers (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Voyager Desktop Planetarium Demo software and manual 1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Knorr "Impact of Islam… " 2/1991 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - miscellaneous articles (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A (Cosmology in Ancient Times) notes, student work (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1987 -1988 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1988 -1989 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1989 -1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1990 -1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1992 -1993 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138A notes, student work 1993 -1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Rational Diameters… " 1/1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - teaching - Ancient Science 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Knorr "Impact of Modern Mathematics… "; "The Greeks (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - teaching - SOC SCI 103 organization (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - miscellaneous articles and papers 1970 -1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Greek -Byzantine bibliography (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - miscellaneous papers, including Knorr "Heronian Algorithm" 6/1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - notes and drafts notebooks #4 -8 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - teaching - Ancient Science, Medieval Science NSLA (New School of Liberal (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - teaching - ancient science, medieval science NSLA notes 12/1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - notes and drafts notebooks #1 -3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - teaching - NSLA 1978 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Archimedes and The Pre -Euclidean Proportion Theory" draft, reprint (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Ratio as a Mathematical Term" Rome Lessico 1992 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - teaching - quizzes, course descriptions 1977 -1978 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - teaching - articles 1977 -1978 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - teaching - Ancient Science NSLA articles, student work 1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Knorr notebook, HIST SCI 110 Harvard 1963 -1964 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - teaching - NSLA notes 1975 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - correspondence 1978 -1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - correspondence 1977 -1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - correspondence and papers 1977 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Archimedes Neusis - Constructions" correspondence 1977 -1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - teaching - Furley, Democritus, Archimedes notebook 1977 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Knorr IBM History Display blueprints and related (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Knorr IBM History Display copy written to date 1979 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Knorr IBM History Display research articles and papers (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - miscellaneous articles and papers 1976 -1979 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Knorr Berkeley notebook 1973 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Two Archimedian Rules" 1/3/1986 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Masi review 3/1983 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Sesiano review 3/1983 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Taisbak review 3/1983 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ferber review 3/1983 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Knorr "What Euclid Meant" 11/1986 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Knorr "What Euclid Meant" proofs, etc. 1986 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Knorr "Ancient Versions of Two Trigonometric Lemmas" 1985 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Knorr "The Medieval Tradition of a Greek Mathematical Lemma" 1987 -1988 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Euclid's Tenth Book" 12/1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Van der Waerden review 1984 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Knorr "Construction as Existence" 1982 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Knorr "Transmission of Geometry… " 1981 -1982 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Fowler "Hibeh… " (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Knorr "Catoptrics" 1984 -1986 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Axiomatics… " 1978 -1980 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Lacroix des Mathematiciens" 1982 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Knorr "Burning Mirrors" (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Knorr "Infinity and Continuity" 1979 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Knorr "Evolution of Euclidean elements" 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Knorr "Hyperbola… "; "Conics… " 1980 -1982 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Tuman "Evolution of Assyro -Babylonian Astronomy" draft and correspondence (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Mesopotamia maps and transparencies (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - ancient astronomy miscellaneous articles, memoranda, newsletters, etc. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Murdoch History of Science course pack 9/1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Murdoch History of Science 106, 107 9/1973 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - teaching - HIS 06 "Time and The Stars" course pack Vol.I Fall 1993 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - teaching - HIS 06 "Time and The Stars" course pack Vol.II Fall 1993 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIS 06 "Time and The Stars" 1993 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Tuman "Introduction to Assyro -Babylonian Astronomy" course packs (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Knorr Textual Studies in Ancient and Medieval Geometry; Ancient Tradition of (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Knorr Textual Studies... and Ancient Tradition... reviews (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Knorr "On the Term 'Ratio'… " 1993 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Thorpe oral exam 1988 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Aganis (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Ptolemy and Apollo (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Knorr "Heptagon… " 1990 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "De Circulo… " 1990 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Knorr "Grosseteste… " 1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Encylopedia Britannica "History of Mathematics" article 1988 -1989 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Knorr Textual Studies... plates (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Knorr Textual Studies... notes 1990 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - teaching - SLE/VTS (Values, Technology and Society) lectures 1981 -1982 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - teaching - HIST 138A 1980 -1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - teaching - HIST 138A 1982 -1983 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - teaching - HIST 138A 1983 -1984 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST 138A 1984 -1985 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - teaching - HIST 138A evaluations 1981 -1995 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - teaching - NSLA Medieval Science Fall 1977 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - teaching - miscellaneous reprints and sources (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - teaching - HIST 138A sources (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - teaching - Stonehenge lecture notes (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - teaching - Egyptian Cosmology and Languages (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HIST 138A course description 1993 -1994 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - teaching - HIST 138A course pack Fall 1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - teaching - HIST 138A course pack 1988 -1989 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - teaching - GREEK 102 1987 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - teaching - GREEK 102 evaluations 1981 -1982 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - teaching - GREEK 101 Fall 1986 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - teaching - GREEK 102, 1982 -1988 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - teaching - GREEK 101 1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - teaching - HIST 138A, 138B student work 1981 -1985 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - teaching - HIST 138A student work 1984 -1993 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Knorr "Textual Studies… " diagrams (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Euclid -Eudoxus bibliography (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Heron Mechanicus (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Knorr "Commentators… " and correspondence 8/1991 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Cameron "Isidore and Hypatia… " and correspondence (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Cameron documents (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Timaeus Classics "Plato's Cosmology" 1990 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Timaeus SJSU (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Timaeus Seattle (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Timaeus England (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Timaeus related essays (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Timaeus "Mythos versus Logos" draft 5/1989 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Atlantis 6/1990 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - IBM History of Mathematics display materials 1981 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Plato and Parmenides White, APA (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - ICHA (International Commission on the History of Mathematics) 1991 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Archimedes biographical 1977 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - De Figuris Ysoperimteris 1989 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - De Figuris Ysoperimteris 1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - John of Tynemouth (aka John of London) BJHS (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - teaching - HUM 163 course pack Spring 1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - teaching - GREEK 155 notes Spring 1988 -1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - teaching - GREEK 155 Plato Spring 1993 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138C (Cosmology) notes 1989 -1991 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138C sources (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - teaching - HIST SCI 138C sources (Box 33, Folder 1)